A Guide to the Records of the Governor's Office, Executive Mansion, 1989-1994
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Governor's Office, Executive Mansion, 1989-1994
The Library of Virginia
35539, 35881
4.5 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Governor L. Douglas Wilder on 31 October 1996.
Scope and Content
Records, 1989-1994, of the Executive Mansion Director during the administration of Governor L. Douglas Wilder. The collection is housed in 10 boxes and includes articles, correspondence, invitations, invoices, lists, memorandums, menus, photographs, and other documents. Collection documents functions held at the Executive Mansion during the Wilder administration; director correspondence regarding the operation of the Mansion; tours of the Mansion; Governor's thank yous for gifts received; records on renovation and refurbishment of the mansion; and related papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Events, 1990-1994
Series II: Director's Correspondence, April-December 1990
Series III: Tours, 1991
Series IV: Governor's Thank Yous for Gifts Received, 1990-1994
Series V: Executive Mansion, 1989-1994
Series VI: General Subjects, 1990-1992
Contents List
- Series I: Events, 1990-1994., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  Events, 1990-1994, contains correspondence, invitations, lists, memorandums, menus, and other documents detailing the scheduling and planning of events held at the Executive Mansion during the Wilder administration, including breakfasts, lunches, dinners, receptions, ceremonies, meetings, and interviews.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Inaugural weekend, 13-14 January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Snacks for Governor Wilder and Family, 13 January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Breakfast with houseguests, 14 January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Press coffee, 24 January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly Black Caucus breakfast, 25 January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Governor and guest dinner, 7 February 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lunch, 10 February 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Assembly leadership reception/meeting, 11 February 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Assembly black tie reception, 19-20 February 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Breakfast (private), 1 March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Congressional delegation meeting/luncheon, 5 March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pages' reception, 6 March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Governor's family and friends brunch, 25 March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Press corps breakfast, 26 March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 17 April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 6 May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Citizens Advisory Council meeting, 25 May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Governor's Fellows cookout, 4 June 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Luncheon with HRH Prince Bandar bin Sultan bin Abdulazia, Ambassador for Saudi Arabia, 21 June 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Governor and guest dinner, 15 July 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Governor's cabinet and key staff meeting, lunch, and dinner, 16 July 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Governor and guests buffet breakfast, 26 July 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Governor's Drug Council meeting and box lunch, 7 August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Citizens Advisory Council meeting--boxed lunches, 16 August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Business Leadership dinner, 24 August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Governor and family with Ebony magazine reporter--breakfast, 25 August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Transportation Pledge Bonds breakfast buffet, 20 September 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - DMV public service announcement filming, 20 September 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Indian payment of taxes ceremony, 20 November 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Governor's holiday greeting to the Commonwealth PSA, 4 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reception after tree lighting, 14 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 17 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Governor's staff candlelight tours, 17-19 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Press corps luncheon, 20 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pre-Christmas dinner, 24 December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - House leadership breakfast meetings, January-February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Senate leadership breakfast meetings, January-February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Foreign policy advisors luncheon, 11 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - House leadership buffet breakfast, 15 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Senate leadership buffet breakfast, 16 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Senate [corrected House] leadership buffet breakfast, 22 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - House [corrected Senate] leadership buffet breakfast, 23 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Congressional delegation meeting and luncheon, 25 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lunch, 26 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Governor and guests brunch, 27 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - House leadership breakfast, 29 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Senate leadership breakfast, 30 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Black Caucus breakfast, 31 January 1991 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Breakfast, 4 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - House leadership breakfast, 5 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Senate leadership breakfast, 6 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Foreign policy luncheon, 8 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - House leadership breakfast, 12 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Senate leadership breakfast, 13 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Pages' breakfast, 14 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Political analysts luncheon, 15 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - House leadership breakfast, 19 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Senate leadership breakfast, 20 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Legislators reception, 20 February 1991 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - CIAA Basketball Tournament reception, 21 February 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Foreign policy luncheon, 15 March 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Citizens Advisory Council reception, 22 March 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Foreign policy luncheon, 26 April 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Union Camp dinner (Department of Economic Development), 29 April 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Governor and guest luncheon, 9 May 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Foreign policy luncheon, 21 May 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jefferson Club reception, 22 May 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Virginia State Library Board luncheon, 15 June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Wilder Exploratory Committee dinner, 17 June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 24 June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ministers' Wives Association tea, 24 June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Wilder Exploratory Committee dinner, 25 June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Governor's Fellows supper, 8 July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wilder Exploratory Committee reception, 23 July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Wilder Exploratory Committee reception and dinner, 30 July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wilder family reunion picnic, 4 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Howard University Law School alumni reception, 14 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 19 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Budget outlook luncheon/meeting, 23 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Going away gathering for Michelle Prosser, 23 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 13th American German Young Leaders Conference tea, 26 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Foreign policy luncheon, 29 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Wilder Exploratory Committee Reception, 29 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wilder for President Exploratory Committee private meeting, 30 August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Physical Fitness Summit, 12 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mansion Council Executive Committee luncheon meeting, 12 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wilder for President Exploratory Committee luncheon and snacks, 13 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Guardsmen tea, 21 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Governor and guest luncheon, 24 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Breakfast with Jesse Jackson, 28 September 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Larry Wilder and guest dinner, 4 October 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chinese delegation meeting with governor, 16 October 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Journalists luncheon, 4 November 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Loren Wilder birthday party, 9 November 1991 (also post-birthday brunch, 10 November 1991) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Loren Wilder post-birthday brunch, 10 November 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Columnists luncheon (Wilder for President Committee), 19 November 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Wilder for President Financial Committee meeting and reception, 25 November 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Indian payment of taxes ceremony, 25 November 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - African American Leadership brunch buffet, 7 December 1991 (rescheduled) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Richmond Area Democratic Woman's Club holiday reception, 8 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Decorations Committee luncheon (boxed), 9 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Wilder for President Committee pre-event reception, 10 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Holiday Tree-Lighting ceremony, 12 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - VMI Tree-Lighting ceremony entertainers dinner, 12 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Christmas Tree-Lighting ceremony--open house for state employees, 12 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Minister of Youth for Angola luncheon, 17 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Governor's office staff holiday reception, 20 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Press luncheon, 23 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Christmas dinner, 25 December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Legislative breakfasts, January-March 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Legislative breakfast, 14 January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Black Caucus buffet breakfast, 16 January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Wilder for President Finance Committee reception, 17 January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Legislative breakfast buffet, 21 January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Legislative breakfast, 28 January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Legislative breakfast, 4 February 1992 (note cancelled) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Congressional delegation coffee, meeting, and luncheon, 7 February 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Walter Lambert and family luncheon, 10 February 1992 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Legislative breakfast, 11 February 1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Ministers luncheon, 11 February 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Pages buffet breakfast, 12 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly Spouses tea, 14 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Larry Wilder luncheon buffet and meeting, 15 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Legislative breakfast, 18 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 18 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Governor and guests breakfast, 20 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner reception, 22 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Legislative breakfast, 25 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CIAA Tournament reception, 28 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Legislative breakfast, 3 March 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Luncheon/interview, 5 March 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Legislators End of Session reception, 6 March 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Paul Goldman-Leslie DiPasqua wedding, 1 April 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Union University basketball team--NCAA Division II champions buffet supper, 16 April 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Democratic National Committee reception, 4 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Abdul Jackson and family luncheon, 7 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Luncheon with Senator John Warner, 8 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - African Ambassadors luncheon, 12 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Citizens Advisory Council box lunch, 13 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Lynn Wilder garden party and buffet brunch (birthday), 16-17 May 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Governor's Business Council, 19 May 1992 (noted as cancelled) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - brunch, [May 1992] (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Bond campaign luncheon, 11 June 1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Virginia State Library tea, 22 June 1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Virginians for Progress Foundation pledge bond reception, 21 July 1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Nigerian delegation luncheon, 27 July 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Governor's Fellows garden barbecue, 29 July 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Stadium Coordinating Committee meeting, 7 August 1992 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Governor's dinner party and brunch for friends, 15-16 August 1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dinner with Walter Witschey (new director of the Science Museum) and wife, 17 August 1992 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Department of Economic Development breakfast, 9 September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Tour hostess seminar, 11 September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Governor and guests breakfast buffet, 16 September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Eddie Williams luncheon, 21 September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Luncheon, 24 September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Transki, South Africa, Businessmen breakfast buffet, 9 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Archbishop Tutu and South African guests dinner, 13 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - West Virginia Governor Gaston Caperton dinner, 14 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bill Clinton presidential debate and breakfast, 15-16 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Makeup hostess seminar and luncheon, 19 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Open House (capitol), 24 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - African Trade Mission reception, 27 October 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Governor's Open House (Harrisonburg), 14 November 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Indian payment of taxe ceremony and reception, 18 November 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Economic Development luncheon, 23 November 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Allied Florists Association box lunches, 7 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Tree Lighting reception, 9 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Open house refreshments for hostesses and entertainers, 11-13 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Governor's open house (Northern Virginia), 12 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Virginia press corps reception, 15 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Richmond Area Democratic Woman's Club reception, 16 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Governor's staff Christmas reception, 18 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Governor and guests dinner, 27 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Governor and guests dinner, 28 December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Virginians for Progress (anti-crime effort) reception, 7 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Black tie receptions, 13-14 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Religious Freedom Day reception, 15 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Martin Luther King reception, 15 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Governor's office open house (Northern Virginia), 23 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Legislative breakfast, 26 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - CAC [Citizens Advisory Council?] luncheon, 27 January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Legislative breakfast, 3 February 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Overnight guests, 4 February 1993 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Arthur Ashe wake and funeral, 9-10 February 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Legislative leadership breakfast, 11 February 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Governor and guests luncheon, 11 February 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Congressional delegation meeting and luncheon, 12 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jeff[erson]-Jackson [Day dinner?], 13 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Agnes Nicholson and friends brunch, 14 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Legislative breakfast, 16 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pages buffet breakfast, 17 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Black Caucus buffet breakfast, 18 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Legislative breakfast, 23 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - CIAA reception, 25 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - End of session reception, 26 February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Governor and guest luncheon, 18 March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Governor and guests breakfast, 21 March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Violent Crime bill signing ceremony and reception, 23 March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bill Cosby visit, 27-28 March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Africare meeting and luncheon, 30 March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hard Road to Glory meeting and luncheon, 1 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sigma Pi Phi black tie cocktails and dinner, 9 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Luncheon with Willie Lanier and Jim Brown, 16 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Governor's open house (Big Stone Gap), 17 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Wedding of Loren Wilder and Edward James--guest list, 24 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Wedding of Loren Wilder and Edward James--guest list, 24 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Wedding of Loren Wilder and Edward James--notes, 24 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Wedding of Loren Wilder and Edward James--miscellaneous, 24 April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Congressman Al Wheat (Maryland) dinner, 29 April 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Film Festival reception and dinner, 13 May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stirrup Cup coffee, 14 May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Governor and guest brunch, 16 May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Judiciary black tie reception, 15 June 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Governor and guests cocktails and hors d'ouevres, 6 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Governor and guests dinner, 15 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - House party at Executive Mansion and Camp Pendleton, 15-18 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Don Graham (Washington Post) luncheon, 23 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Governor's Fellows dinner, 26 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Brown v. Board of Education 40th Anniversary Steering Committee luncheon, 27 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - TV-8 taping of governor, 28, 30 July 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Slavery museum meeting, luncheon, reception, and dinner, 3 August 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Governor and neighbors cocktails and dinner, 24 August 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Camp Pendleton, 4-6 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Executive Institute reception, 9 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Howard University luncheon, 10 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Southern Governors Association and African heads of state summit special mansion tours, 19 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - African heads of state formal dinner, 21 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Governor and special guests reception, 25 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Governor and guests brunch, 26 September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Ville Giardini magazine photo shoot of Executive Mansion, 1 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Hostess orientation and luncheon, 7 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Governor's Advisory Board of Economists, 20 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Mickey Mouse meeting with at-risk youth, 22 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gold Bowl reception, 23 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - HBO Sports filming--Arthur Ashe documentary, 29 October 1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Fortune 500 spouses luncheon, 5 November 1993 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Governor's Hispanic appointees, 10 November 1993 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Richmond Area Deomcratic Woman's Club holiday reception, 19 December 1993 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gifted children's reception, 10 January 1994 (originally scheduled 29 December 1993, rescheduled due to inclement weather) (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - End of administration reception, 12 January 1994 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Event blank form (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Series II: Director's correspondence, April-December 1990., Extent: 1 box. (Box 8)
  Director's correspondence, April-December 1990, contains correspondence and memorandums to and from director Cathy Walker Green regarding the day-to-day operations and activities at the Executive Mansion.
  - Director's correspondence, April 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Director's correspondence, May 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Director's correspondence, June 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Director's correspondence, July 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Director's correspondence, August 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Director's correspondence, September 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Director's correspondence, October 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Director's correspondence, November 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Director's correspondence, December 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series III: Tours, 1991., Extent: 1 box. (Box 8)
  Tours, 1991, contains correspondence requesting and confirming tours of the Executive Mansion for various groups, such as school groups and civic organizations. Also includes thank you letters for the tours.
  - Tours, January 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Tours, February 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Tours, March-May 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Tours, June-August 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Tours, September-December 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Governor's Thanks Yous for Gifts Received, 1990-1994., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 9-10)
  Governor's Thanks Yous for Gifts Received, 1990-1994, contains correspondence, lists, memorandums, and other documents, consisting of thank you replies for gifts received by Governor Wilder.
  - Correspondence--Governor's gifts, 1990 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Governor's gifts, 1990 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Governor's gifts--grey freezer inventory, 1 July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Governor's thank yous--holiday thank yous, December 1991-January 1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Governor's thank yous, January 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Governor's thank yous, February-March 1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Governor's thank yous, April 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Governor's thank yous, May 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Governor's thank yous, June 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Governor's thank yous, July 1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Governor's thank yous, August 1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Governor's thank yous, September 1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Governor's thank yous, October-November 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Governor's thank yous, December 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cabinet gift, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series V: Executive Mansion, 1989-1994., Extent: 1 box. (Box 10)
  Executive Mansion, 1989-1994, contains budgets, correspondence, inventories, memorandums, and other papers concerning the renovation and refurbishment of the Mansion during the Wilder administration; operating budget for 1992; inventory of Wilder's personal property; and security, staffing, and tours.
  - Executive Mansion renovations and alterations, February 1990-August 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Executive Mansion Refurbishing briefing of the Governor, 16 March 1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Executive Mansion budget, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Inventory of governor's personal property, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Security, 12 March 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Staff transition, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Staff on duty[?], December 1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Staff blank time sheet (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Training for new Mansion telephone system, 7 March 1990 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Tour for NBA wives--correspondence, 5 August 1992 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Series VI: General Subjects, 1990-1992., Extent: 1 box. (Box 10)
  General Subjects, 1990-1992, contains governor's meal schedules, recipes, memorandums on a birthday party and on a bowling team, inventory of Pendleton Cottage located in Virginia Beach, Virginia, and implementation manual and training program manuel from Pennsylvania for the Americans With Disabilities Act.